NNAEMEKA OKALLA

Software Engineer

DETAILS

emyokalla@gmail.com 💌

linkedin.com/in/emmy-okalla in

github.com/emytek (7)

PROFILE

Diverse Software Engineer with professional experience building software solutions. Open-minded, easily adapting to changes, adopting new technologies, and interested in solving real-world problems with software. Experienced in developing, testing, and debugging code; designing user interfaces, handling big data, and geospatial analysis, and administering systems and networks.

EDUCATION

Master's Degree in Geographic Information System (MSc | MGIS),

University of Lagos

Bachelor's Degree Hons (BSc) in Geoinformatics,

University of Nigeria

Thesis: Production of an interactive web-based map of the University of Nigeria

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Software Engineer at Kropmann, Lagos

July 2021 — Present

- Engaged with a distributed team of engineers building customer-centric lifestyle products for subscription, payment and remittance with over 1000 daily users.
- Implement Agile methodology, coordinate sprints, delegate tasks, and perform code reviews all increasing productivity by about 35%.
- Improved and modified features in the existing system with Node JS
 while piloting scalable and efficient RESTful services and APIs and
 designing pixel-perfect user interfaces and layouts for software
 products.
- Liaise with Product Managers to identify and draft minimum viable product requirements and clearly translate features into well-scoped user stories for a 100% market-fit product.
- Planned, analysed, monitored and updated the geospatial details of smallworld GIS, a custom fibre network inventory solution

Backend Developer at Novugrid, (remote)

March 2019 — May 2021

- Worked with an Agile team of over 8 distributed NodeJS and Flutter engineers as well as React and Vue developers to build web applications.
- Engineered, deployed and integrated multiple RESTful services
 with Node js and Express for solutions ranging from e-commerce
 to internet banking and general financial software solutions,
 Logistics and events such as crawl, Internet payments and
 Logistics (De Wallet) and Digital Trade by Barter System (Baater)
 with over 10,000 daily users.
- Set up automated Continuous deployment and integration pipelines with GitHub Actions to improve productivity by 23%.
- Collaborated with stakeholders on software design and architecture best suited for the particular product for optimal product and 100% user satisfaction.

SKILLS

HTML CSS

Javascript

React js

Vue js

Angular

Node js Express

. MongoDB

MySQL

PostgreSQL

AWS

Microservices

JSON

REST API

GraphQL

Agile and Scrum

DevOps

CERTIFICATIONS

Meta Frontend Development
Oracle Cloud Solutions Architect
IBM Fullstack Development
Nigeria Space Research
Development Agency (NARSDA)
Geoinfotech (Python in GIS)

Web Developer Intern at HIIT, Lagos

August 2018 — February 2019

- Improved code base with modern ES6 features and syntax while observing best practices and enhancing code efficiency.
- Engaged in brainstorming sessions, learning industry standards for design, testing, optimization, debugging and deploying code with members of the team.
- Participating and contributing in rigorous code reviews and researching on various software engineering principles and applications of web technologies.